At the end of the world his real journey began.
Seven Years in Tibet is a adventure, drama, history
film directed by Jean-Jacques Annaud.
Austrian mountaineer Heinrich Harrer journeys to the Himalayas
without his family to head an expedition in 1939.
But when World War II breaks out, the arrogant Harrer falls
into Allied forces' hands as a prisoner of war.
He escapes with a fellow detainee and makes his way to Lhasa, Tibet, where he meets the
14-year-old Dalai Lama, whose friendship ultimately transforms his outlook on life.
Heinrich Harrer, played by Brad Pitt.
Dalai Lama, 14 Years Old, played by Jamyang Jamtsho Wangchuk.
Peter Aufschnaiter, played by David Thewlis.
Ngawang Jigme, played by BD Wong.
Kungo Tsarong, played by Mako.
Pema Lhaki, played by Lhakpa Tsamchoe.
Seven Years in Tibet is a 1997 American biographical war
drama film directed by Jean-Jacques Annaud.
It is based on Austrian mountaineer and Schutzstaffel (SS) sergeant Heinrich Harrer's 1952
memoir of the same name, about his experiences in Tibet between 1944 and 1951.
Seven Years in Tibet stars Brad Pitt and David Thewlis, and has music composed
by John Williams with a feature performance by cellist Yo-Yo Ma.
In the film, Harrer (Pitt) and fellow Austrian Peter Aufschnaiter
(Thewlis) are mountaineering in the 1930s India.
When World War II begins in 1939, their German citizenship results in their
imprisonment in a British prisoner-of-war camp in Dehradun in the Himalayas.
In 1944, Harrer and Aufschnaiter escape the prison and cross the border
into Tibet, traversing the treacherous high plateau.
There, after initially being ordered to return to India, they are welcomed at the
holy city of Lhasa and become absorbed into an unfamiliar way of life.
Harrer is introduced to the 14th Dalai Lama, still a
boy, and becomes one of his tutors.
During their time together, Heinrich becomes a close
friend to the young spiritual leader.
Harrer and Aufschnaiter stay in the country until the Battle of Chamdo in 1950.
The film explores themes of himalaya mountain range, buddhism,
buddhist monk, world war ii, prisoner of war.
The tone is emotional.